tandfonline.com 2015-07-17

# Privacy Policy & Cookies | Taylor & Francis Online

**Taylor & Francis Online Privacy Policy**

Taylor & Francis Online is owned and operated by Informa UK Limited whose registered office is 5 Howick Place, London, SW1P 1WG. This policy (together with our terms and conditions and any other documents referred to in it) explains how we will collect, process, use, and protect your personal information when you use our website and register to use our website ("Taylor & Francis Online") and any material published therein.

 **1 Your personal information  
**

1.1 When you register on our website, we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, age, address, organization, or employer, phone number, credit card, or other payment information and a password (where a login has been provided) ("Personal Information"). We may also collect other information, including, but not limited to, the URL you came from, IP address, your browser type, country, and telephone area code where your computer is located and the pages of our website that you viewed.

1.2 We may supplement the information that you provide us with information that we receive from third parties.

 **2 Acceptance of terms  
**

By using our website or submitting information to us, you:

2.1 agree to accept the data protection practices outlined in this Privacy Policy; and 

2.2 consent to our collecting and processing your Personal Information in connection with the sale and distribution of Informa's services and products; 

**3 Use of your information  
**

3.1 We may use the information that you provide or that we collect for the following purposes:

3.1.1 to register you with Taylor & Francis Online, to set up and manage your Informa account, and to administer our Informa products and services;

3.1.2 to provide any services or information you have requested;

3.1.3 to notify you about our products or special offers that may be of interest to you, customer services and profiling your purchasing preferences;

3.1.4 to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

3.1.5 for detecting and protecting against error, fraud or other criminal activity;

3.1.6 to enforce our terms and conditions of use, including carrying out security reviews to validate your identity, age, contact details, and financial information; or

3.1.7 in any other way as described to you at the time of collection of your Personal Information.

3.2 We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to assist us in providing you with any Informa service.

3.3 Your email address will be used to notify you of essential service information and any alerts you have requested. You may also, from time to time, receive information on services and offers available to you from Informa.

3.4 If you do not want us to contact you with details of our special offers, products, or services that we think you might be interested in, please tick the relevant box on the registration form or contact us at the address below.

 **4 Disclosure of your information  
**

4.1 We may give information about you to the following, who may use it for the same purposes as set out above:

4.1.1 to agents and employees of Informa to administer any accounts, products, and services provided to you now or in the future;

4.1.2 to agents who profile your data so that we may tailor the goods/services we offer to your specific needs;

4.1.3 to anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you;

4.1.4 if we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction;

4.1.5 to third parties who will help process or administer Informa services.

4.2 When you submit sensitive information via the website (such as a credit card number), the information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL.

4.3 While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked, or open, as will be the case for most of the time that a user is browsing the web.

 **5 Cookies**

5.1 When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful, and reliable. Where services are delivered on the Internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through (for example):

5.1.1 enabling a service to recognize your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task

5.1.2 recognizing that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested

5.1.3 measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast

If you do not accept cookies you will be unable to use this website. You can, however, manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through [Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them](http://www.direct.gov.uk/managingcookies).

5.2 Our use of cookies

5.2.1 Important information about this list of cookies. This list is not yet complete. It will be updated as further information is gathered from companies we work with.

5.2.2 Cookies for measuring use of services. By understanding how people use Taylor & Francis Online, we can improve the information provided. This also ensures that the service is available when you want it and fast. We use a number of different methods of gathering this data; see below for details:

 **Title of   cookie  
**|  **Purpose of cookie  
**|  **Type of cookie  
**|  **Does the cookie link to other data the provider holds on the individual?  
**|  **Lifespan of cookie  
**|  **First party/third party  
**  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
JSESSIONID  
| Performance optimization  
| Performance optimization & currently also used to collect information on how site is used by user.  
| Yes, but only temporarily  
| Session  
| First party  
  
MAID  
| Targeting relevant content/services  
| Customization  
| Yes  
| 300 days  
| First party  
  
SERVER  
| Performance optimization  
| Performance optimization & currently also used to collect information on how site is used by user.  
| No  
| Session  
| First party  
  
__utma  
| User tracking: analytics  
| Google Analytics  
| No  
| 2 years  
| Third party  
  
__utmb  
| User tracking: analytics  
| Google Analytics  
| No  
| 20 minutes  
| Third party  
  
__utmc  
| User tracking: analytics  
| Google Analytics  
| No  
| Session  
| Third party  
  
__utmz  
| User tracking: analytics  
| Google Analytics  
| No  
| 180 days  
| Third party  
  
AUTO_SIGNIN  
| "Remember me"  
| Set when the user explicitly requests that the website "remember me"  
| Yes  
| 1 year  
| First party  
SFFID  
| Out-of-network access  
| Set upon arrival to the website. It is used to enable access to protected content while the user is connected to the website from outside of an institutional network. Note: This cookie is also used to collect information about how visitors use the website. We are working to change this behavior.  
| Yes  
| 1 year  
| First party  
MobileUI  
| Mobile-optimized UI  
| Set upon arrival to the website using a mobile device. It is used to record the visitor's preference for using the mobile-optimized version of the website.  
| No  
| Session  
| First party  
  
 **6 Access to information  
**

You have the right to make a written request for a copy of the Personal Information that we keep about you (for which we may, at our sole discretion, charge a small fee of £10) or to correct the details that we hold about you.

 **7 Changes to this Privacy Policy  
**

We reserve the right to update, modify, and/or change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any such changes will be posted here. If you continue to use an Informa service after we have changed this Privacy Policy, you hereby consent to be bound by any such changes.

 **8 Security**

8.1 We will protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access by using commercially reasonable security measures. If your Personal Information is accessed by an unauthorized third party, we will not be responsible for any direct or indirect damage caused as a result of such unauthorized access.

8.2 Where we have given you a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

8.3 Unfortunately the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to our site. Any transmission will be at your own risk.

 **9 Contacting us  
**

All questions, comments, and requests regarding this Privacy Policy should be addressed to [support@tandfonline.com](mailto:support@tandfonline.com).

For a downloadable copy, you can select the PDF here....  

Please also read our Terms and Conditions.
